Gerson Ramirez

Download the most updated version following the link on the name.

Sun Vista, Las Vegas, NV, 89104

Phone (s) **Email** Cell: 7023218287 (preferred contact hours: 1:00pm - 6:30pm PST on weekdays, and weekends) antillgrp@gmail.com (preferred contact)

Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bcs-gerson-ramirez

GitHub https://github.com/antillgrp



Currently coursing Master of Science in Software Development (GPA: 4.0 (Gerson_Unofficial_Transcript_8_26_2020.pdf)) holding a Bachelor's in Computer Science professional with more than ten years of experience in many different IT areas, such as software development, systems and networking.

At present looking for a role change with new opportunities and goals to reach:

Software development skills and competences:

- Expertise in OOP and Functional languages like Java (Springboot, Hibernate, JPA, etc.), NodeJS, Python, C#, TypeScript, among others.
- Advanced knowledge in BackEnd FrontEnd integration with trends opensource libraries like ReactJS (JS, TS, Redux, React-Router, React-Bootstrap, React-Material-UI, etc.), VueJS. Knowledge of web services with solid understanding of the RESTful Architecture and **SOAP.** Knowledgeable in **full stack development**, **platforms**, **frameworks and front-end libraries**. Java frameworks. .Net Framework, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, Entity Framework, NodeJS (back-end libraries like express, sequelize and many others).
- Strong knowledge Object-Oriented Paradigm, SOLID adherence and GoF Design Patterns. Comprehensive experience with Databases design and administration and DB query languages, such as MS SQL Server and MySQL. High proficiency using IDEs and debugging tools, Microsoft Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, NetBeans, etc.
- Accredited certifications for Docker & Kubernetes Workshop and Springboot and Microservices.
- (In progress) AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator

IT Technician skills and competences:

- Extensive experience as Server-Racks/Network-Rack Technician (Hardware, Software), computer service, technical support.
- Extensive experience as a Computer Support Technician. Network and Systems Administrator. Operating Systems, Cisco
- IOS, Windows Servers OS, Linux, Unix, BSD, others.
- Network Services configuration and deployment such as Email (SMTP, POP3, IMAP), Web IIS, (LAMP STACK), NODE.JS,
- FTP Servers. Network design and Security, Firewalling. Virtualization and Cloud VmWare (esxi, VSphere), HyperV and others.

!! Federal ACTIVE Department of Commerce (DoC) Moderate Background Investigation (MBI) Public Trust clearance.

To inquire further regarding verification of clearance, please contact Census Investigative Services (CIS).

Work experience

Functions and main responsibilities

Last positions held

Occupation or position held

IT Systems/Network/Hardware Technician level II Enterprise Area (06/2016 to current)

- Application development cross-training (6 weeks) (C#. ASP.NET Web API, SQL SERVER. JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY)
- Install, configure troubleshoot and upgrade Server/Racks hardware, software, networks (routers/switches/wireless) and peripheral equipment.
- Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) CDW in configuration center.

Employer

References and contacts available on request

Occupation or position held

Broadband Premises Installer (08/2015 to 06/2016) IES Residential, Inc. - Las Vegas, NV Contact: Amaury Arencibia (Supervisor): +1-702-485-9266

Education and Training

Major Degree: Bachelor's in Computer Science (07/2009)

Certifications and Standard Education (most recent)













ReactJS with **Redux** Certification (02/2019)

JAVA Object Oriented App **Development**

TCP/IP and Red Had Linux

Red Had Linux **Administration Level 1**

CCNA(CISCO training modules).

98-366: MTA: Networking **Fundamentals** SCTE Cable Technician, **Broadband Premises** Installer

- (In progress) AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator
 - **Docker & Kubernetes Workshop**
- (02/2019) ReactJS with Redux Certification Training
- CDW application development cross-training (6 weeks)
- Object Oriented Application Development
- 98-366: MTA: Networking Fundamentals

- **Springboot and Microservices**
- CCNA (CISCO Course modules) (270 h)
- TCP/IP and Red Had Linux Essential
- Red Had Linux Administration Level 1
- Microsoft WS 2008 Network Services Administration Course
- Microsoft WS 2008 Active Directory Administration Course

Work Experience	
Occupation or position held	IT Systems/Network/Hardware Enterprise Technician level II (4/2016 to -)
Functions and main responsibilities	 Install, upgrade, configure and troubleshoot hardware and software, for Racks, Servers, networks and peripheral equipment. Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards printers)
Employer	CDW in configuration center.
Occupation or position held	Broadband Premises Installer (08/2015 to)
Functions and main responsibilities	 Install and troubleshoot telecommunications services (video, voice, and data) at the customer's premis Cable Technician. Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboard printers)
Employer	IES Residential, Inc Las Vegas, NV Contact: Amaury Arencibia (Supervisor) : +1-702-485-9266
Occupation or position held	<u>Non IT</u> (02/2015 to 07/2015)
Occupation or position held	Non IT (11/2014 to 07/2015) on-call
Occupation or position held	Computer Technician/Web Developer (01/01/2013 to 09/30/2014)
	- Web applications development CMS based, joomla, drupal, wordpress.
	- Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows, Linux, MacOS, Unix (FreeBSD) Installation and configuration of wired and wireless networks, and network equipment.
Functions and main responsibilities	- Repairing and maintaining all sort of computer equipment.
	- Remote Assistance and Customer Support.
	- Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards printers)
Employer	<u>freelance</u> (customers references only)
Occupation or position held Functions and main responsibilities	IT Systems and Hardware Technician/Web Developer (03/01/2011 to 12/31/2012) - Small web applications development CMS based, joomla, drupal, wordpress. - Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows, Linux, MacOS, Unix (FreeBSD) - Installation and configuration of wired and wireless networks, and network equipment. - Repairing and maintaining all sort of computer equipment. - Remote Assistance and Customer Support. - Selling and post sales support. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboard printers)
Employer	Informática Profesional de Canarias.
Occupation or position held	System Technician and Final User Support (06/01/10 to 07/30/10)
Functions and main responsibilities	 Small web applications development CMS based, joomla, drupal, wordpress. Member of the team in charge of the migration and deploying of "Drago" System (Unified and centralized system of health information), Canary Islands Health Service. Also, giving technical onsite customer support. Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers)
Employer	Arcitel Ibérica, S.A, Tenerife (Spain)
Occupation or position held	Dependent Technical of Cybercafe (retailer IT shop) (05/09 to 05/10)
Functions and main responsibilities	 Selling and Customer attention. Systems Installation and Configuration, O.Systems Windows. Installation and configuration of wired and wireless networks, and network equipment. Repairing and maintaining all sort of computer equipment. Remote Assistance and Customer Support. Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers)
Employer	Cybercafe Cybermar, Tenerife (Spain)
Occupation or position held	Network and Systems Administrator and Management Computing (04/2008 to 04/2009)

Functions and main responsibilities Employer	- Internet enterprises services management (email, web, others) - Administration and maintenance physical (cable, routers, switches) and logical network (active directory, users, group policy, security, databases systems, others) Analysis and implementation of projects (see Degree Project (Spanish)) - Computing equipment purchasing management Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers) ICM (Instituto Cubano de la Música), Ministerio de Cultura., Havana (Cuba)
Occupation or position held	
Functions and main responsibilities	Network and Systems technician specialist (07/2007 to 03/2008) - Implementing, deploying and administration of mail, web and mailing list Unix servers (Freebsd and Linux) in a dedicated Datacenter. (see Degree Project (Spanish)) - Networking maintenance. - Huge rollouts of memory installation/upgrade, peripheral equipment swapped out (monitors, keyboards, printers)
Employer	CUBARTE (Centro de Informática para la Cultura), Min. de Cultura, Habana (Cuba)
Education and Training	
Major Degree	Computer Science Degree
(07/2009) 5 Years	 Bachelor of Computer Science Subjects Included: Programming, Object Oriented Programming. (Java and .NET). Web design and Full-Stack development. Relational Database (Relational Algebra and Calculus, Normalized design and Standardization). Management Systems (SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle). Connectivity High-level languages (Java, .Net, JavaScript, PHP, TypeScript). Systems for Advanced Data Bases (Relational-Object Mapping (Hibernate, ADO.NET Entity Framework), Object Oriented, Logical-Deductive). Logic Programming (Prolog) and functional (Hashkell). Distributed Systems (GRID). Software Engineering and Project Analysis. Detection and repair hardware problems and hardware. Network and Systems Administration. (Servers Linux, Unix and Windows, Network Architectures OSI and TCP / IP, etc.). Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Havana
09/04/2012-30/07/2012 (270 h)	EXPERTO EN CONFIGURACIÓN DE REDES CISCO CCNA (EXPERT CISCO CCNA NETWORK CONFIGURATION) Subjects Included: • Full content of the four official modules of CCNA certification. Canary Institute for Professional Development (ICADEPRO) Diploma of Achievement.
02/2012 (32 h) 02/2012 (32 h)	Microsoft WS 2008 Network Services Administration Training Subjects Included: • Implementation and Management of Network Services Microsoft Windows Server 2008. Fundación Canaria de Formación y Empleo (FOREM) Diploma of Achievement. Microsoft WS 2008 System Components Administration Training Subjects Included:
	Tools and general issues of Windows Server systems. Microsoft Windows Server 2008. Fundación Canaria de Formación y Empleo (FOREM) Diploma of Achievement.
03/2012 (32 h)	Microsoft WS 2008 Active Directory Administration Trainig Subjects Included: Reaffirmation and certification of my knowledge in Systems Management and Windows Server 2008 Active Directory updated to Microsoft Windows Server 2008. Fundación Canaria de Formación y Empleo (FOREM)

Page 3/4 - Resume of Gerson Ramirez. - June 2020

	Diploma of Achievement.
03/2007- 05/2007 (96 h)	TCP/IP and Red Had Linux Essential Subjects Included: • Basic network administration and Linux operating systems CUBA-INDIA Center Knowledge NIIT (NIIT - FORDES, Centre for Training and Development, Ministry of Informatics and Communications) International Certificate of Competence.
06/2007- 08/2007 (96 h)	Red Had Linux Administration Level 1 Subjects Included: • Basic network administration and Linux operating systems CUBA-INDIA Center Knowledge NIIT (NIIT - FORDES, Centre for Training and Development, Ministry of Informatics and Communications) International Certificate of Competence.
10/2007- 12/2007 (96 h)	Object Oriented Application Development Subjects Included: • Developing Applications with Java object-oriented programming. (Notices of recognition for outstanding projects) CUBA-INDIA Center Knowledge NIIT (NIIT - FORDES, Centre for Training and Development, Ministry of Informatics and Communications) International Certificate of Competence.
Skills Communication skills	 Excellent verbal and written communication in Spanish skills both in an office environment and with external stakeholders. Advanced (still learning) verbal and written communication in English skills both in an office environment and with external stakeholders. Team work: I have worked many times in multidisciplinary teams, even leading, with good results. Good telephone manner.
rganizational / managerial skills	 Effective time management, prioritizing skills and abilities to concurrently work with restricted deadlines. Self-motivated, team worker, problem-solving, can-do attitude, and excellent communication skills. Active and fast learner and researcher. High adaptability to new processes, latest technologies, trends.

Or